Guide to the Paul Cooper papers, 1943-1995 MS 463
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Paul Cooper papers
1943-1995
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Cooper, Paul
MS 463
14 Linear Feet 33 boxes
Paul Cooper's papers document his professional career as a composer, music critic, author and teacher, at Rice University, University of Michigan, and University of Cincinnati. Formats include correspondence, compositions (scores), course notes and outlines, photographs, notes, performance, programs, and sound recordings; dates range from 1943-1995.
Biographical / Historical
Paul Cooper (1926-96), composer-in-residence and Lynette Autrey Professor of Music at Rice University, was internationally known as a composer, music critic, author and teacher. He earned degrees from the University of Southern California and studied at the Conservatoire Nationale and the Sorbonne in Paris, and made his professional debut in 1953 with the Los Angeles Philharmonic. He was a music critic in Los Angeles and Ann Arbor, MI and taught at the University of Michigan (1955-68) and the College-Conservatory of Music at the University of Cincinnati before joining the Rice faculty in 1974. Cooper held guest professorships in Stockholm and Copenhagen. He received Fulbright and Guggenheim Fellowships, grants from the National Endowment for the Arts, Ford, Rockefeller and Rackham Foundations and the National Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, and 25 consecutive ASCAP awards beginning in 1966. He served as cultural representative to Yugoslavia for the US State Department in 1965, and in 1976 began his involvement with the Music Teachers National Association. He served on the boards of Meet-the-Composer [Texas], Houston Composers Alliance, Voices of Change, Texas Composers Forum, and Phi Beta Kappa Alumni of Houston. Cooper was married to the former Christiane Ebert, a noted poet with whom he collaborated on oratorios, song cycles, instrumentals and chamber works. They have two children.
Scope and Contents
Paul Cooper's papers document his professional career as a composer, music critic, author and teacher, at Rice University, University of Michigan, and University of Cincinnati. Formats include correspondence, compositions, course notes and outlines, photographs, notes, performance, programs, and sound recordings; dates range from 1943-1995.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
No access restrictions; this material is open for research.
Related Materials
The Joseph Lomax papers (MS ) contains a score written by Cooper, a solo organ piece called In Nomine, which was commissioned by Joseph Lomax.
Index Terms
Subjects
Music -- Instruction and study; Composers; Music
Document Types
scores; programs (documents); sheet music; corrrespondence; sound recordings; photographs; notes
Subjects (Persons)
Cooper, Paul; Cooper, Paul
Subjects (Corporations)
Shepherd School of Music
- Series I: Correspondence, Professional, 1950-1995
  - Subseries A: General, 1950s-1990s
    - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1970s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1980-83 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1984-85 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1986-89 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Named correspondents, 1952-1995
    - Ross Lee Finney, 1966-95, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Re: Boulanger, 1952-53 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Publishers-Dodd, Mead Co., 1968-75 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Publishers-Wilhelm Hansen, 1971-88 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Publishers-Harper Row, 1975-87 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Publishers-copyright cleared to Harper Row, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Publishers-general, 1963-95 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - ASCAP [American Society of Composers, Authors Publishers], 1970-88 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - MTNA [Music Teachers National Association] Executive Board, 1972-84 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - MTNA National Commissioning, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - MTNA-general, 1970s-80s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series II: Rice University, 1978-1995
  - [PC's] Reports to the President, 1982, 88, 90-92, 94-95 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Recommendations, 1983/84-84/85 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Tenure and Chair meetings, 1983/84-84/85 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Composition/Theory staff meetings, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Departmental meetings, 1990-91 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Theory department, 1991-92 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fondren Library Committee, 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Music degree programs, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence [Rice only], 1978-79, 81-86, 88-89, 91-93, 95 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Lectures, 1981, 83, 85 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Shepherd School faculty minutes, 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Shepherd School faculty minutes, 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Shepherd School -misc. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Greater Houston Assoc.), Rice chapter, 1983/84 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, Rice chapter, 1984/85 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - SYZYGY, 1983-84 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - SYZYGY, "Meet the Composer," 1991-92 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - SYZYGY concert programs (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Festival of American Contemporary Music (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Rice-related concert programs (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Series III: Teaching Materials, 1957-1995
  - Subseries A: University of Michigan course notes and outlines, 1957-1967
    - 1957 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1965 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: University of Cincinnati course notes and outlines, 1969-1974
    - Teaching project, 1969-70 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Course notes and outlines, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Course notes and outlines, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Rice University course notes and outlines, 1976-1995
    - 1976-79 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1980s (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1990s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - [PC's] Sample examinations (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Personal, 1950-1995
  - Vitae (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Thesis (Master's), 1953 and graduate recital programs, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Literary writings (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Music Literature for Sight Singing, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Keyboard Music of Paul Cooper, John Carbon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Military (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - School papers (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Seminar and class notes (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Honors (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Newsclips (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Insurance and household (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Income tax (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Grant applications (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Catalogs listing Cooper's works (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Reviews written by Cooper (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Reviews of Cooper's works (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Reviews of Cooper's works (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1980s (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1980s (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, 1990s (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Programs from performances of Cooper's works, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Posters advertising Cooper's concerts (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Series V: Compositions (scores and recordings), 1943-1993
  - Subseries A: Standard sized scores
    - All the Day I Hear, 9-48 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Canti for Viola and Piano, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Celebration, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Chorales of Nativity, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Concert for Three, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Concerto for Antiphonal Organs, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Concerto for Flute and Orchestra, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Credo, 8-18-70 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Double Concerto for Violin, Viola and Orchestra, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Duo Concertante, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Elegies, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Etude No. 1, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Folio of compositions for class, 1948-49 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Folk Dances, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Four Impromptus, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - From the Sacred Harp, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Glory to God, 6-18-44 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Impressions, 7-18-44 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Jubilate, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Last Call; Arias and Recitatives on Poems of C.E. Cooper, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Love Songs and Dances, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Minuet for Catie's White Square, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Missa Brevis, n.d. (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Momment Musical, 8-7-44 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Music for a Festive Occasion, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Mysterion, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Nocturne No. 3, 7-16-44 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Nun Danket, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Organ Concerto, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Piano Sonata, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Prayer, 12-10-43 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Prelude for Two Pianos, 8-43 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Quartet, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Quartet No. 1, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Quartet No. 2, 1954, revised 3-31-79 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Quartet No. 4, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Quartet No. 6, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Quintet, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Quodlibet, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Requiem for Organ Percussion, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Rhapsody on a Folk Theme, 7-7-44 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Rondel Bergamasques, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Saxophone Concerto, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Scherzo, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Serenade for flute, clarinet, violin, viola, cello and piano, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Serenade on a Theme of Carrie Jacobs Bond, 3-47 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Seven Songs, 11-20-46 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Seventeen Haiku, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - The Seventh Psalm, 4-2-44 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Silences, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Sinfonia, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Sinfonia for Strings, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Soliloquies for Violin and Piano, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Sonata, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Sonata da Camera for Harpsichord, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Sonata Fantasy for Two Pianos, 2-7-44 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Sonata for Double Bass and Piano, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sonata for Viola and Piano, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sonnets, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Sonnets for Piano, 7-31-47 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - String Quartet No. 1, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Suite for Piano, 2-47 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Symphony in Two Movements, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Symphony No. 6, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Theme, Variations Toccata, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Three Alleluias for solo organ, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Three Intermezzi, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Three Sonatas for piano, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Tomorrow's Songs, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Tre Voci, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Tre Voci, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Umbrae, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Variants IV, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Variations for Violin and Piano, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Versés, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Violin Sonata 3, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Voyages; on a text by C.E. Cooper, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - We Pray to Thee, 7-5-44 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Winter Poems, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Subseries B: Oversized working copies of scores (Box 15-23)
    - Canons d'Amour, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Cello Sonata, n.d. [incomplete]
    - Canti for Viola and Piano, 1981
    - Chamber Music, 1982
    - The Color of Gold, n.d.
    - Concert for Five, 1964
    - Concerto for Cello and Orchestra, 1977
    - Concerto for Flute and Oboe, n.d.
    - Concerto for Flute and Orchestra, 1980
    - Concerto for Organ and Orchestra, 1982
    - Credo, n.d. (see also Box 23)
    - Danse, 9-22-95
    - Descants, 1975
    - Dialogues for Violoncello and Double Wind Quintet, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Double Concerto for Violin, Viola and Orchestra, 1987
    - Double Concerto, 1985-87
    - Duo Concertante for Violin, Viola and Orchestra, 1985
    - Duo Concerto, n.d.
    - Equinox for Chorus, Flute, Cello and Piano, 1976
    - Four Impromptus, 1983 (Box 17)
    - [Four] Impromptus, 1983
    - Incidental Music for "The Woman of Andros," n.d.
    - In Nomine, 1984
    - Jubilate, 1986 [with various instrumental parts]
    - Landscape Symphony No. 4, 1975
    - Last Call; Arias and Recitatives on Poems of C.E. Cooper, 1990
    - Love Songs and Dances, 1986
    - Love Songs and Dances, 1985-86 (Box 18)
    - Mirrors, 1986
    - Music for a Festive Occasion, n.d.
    - Mysterion, 1988
    - Ode for Orchestra, 10-20-43
    - Ode for Orchestra, n.d.
    - O Men from the Fields!, 1948
    - Organ Concerto, 1982 (Box 19)
    - Overture, 1953
    - Overture, 1953 [violin I]
    - Overture, 1953 [cello]
    - Piano Quintet, 1994
    - Piano Quintet, 1995
    - Prèlude pour le piano, 1993
    - Quartet No. 2, 1954, rev. 1979
    - Quodlibet, 1989
    - Saxophone Concerto, 1982
    - Serenade, 1993 [parts] (Box 20)
    - Seventeen Haiku, 1987, 89
    - Silences, n.d.
    - Sinfonia for solo piano, 1989
    - Sonata, 1961
    - Sonata for Cello and Piano, 1963
    - Sonata No. 2 for Piano, n.d.
    - Songs of Antigone, 1979
    - Symphony in Two Movements, 1982-83
    - Symphony No. 2, 8-56 [PC's dissertation for Doctor of Musical Arts, University of Southern California] (Box 21)
    - Symphony No. 6, 1987
    - Toccata, 1989
    - To Everything, 1987
    - Three Alleluias for solo organ, 1993
    - Three Rondels Bergamasques, 1988
    - Di Tre Voci, 1984
    - Tre Voci, 1987
    - Variants IV, 1985 (Box 22)
    - Variations on an Aire, 9-5-45
    - Umbrae (String Quartet No. 5), 1973
    - Voyagers, 1982-83
    - Winter Poems, 1984
    - Untitled and incomplete works (4)
    - Credo, 1970 (Box 23)
    - Desk calendars, 1985-95
    - Dreaming, John Carbon, 1985
    - String Quartet No. 1, Mark Bradshaw, 1987
    - LP record album: CRI-SD 369A/B, 6-22-77
    - LP record album: Sinphonia for Strings, 1/3, 2/3
    - LP record album: Quartet No. 4, written in memory of John Fitzgerald Kennedy, 1964
    - LP record album: Test pressing #402
    - LP record album: Concerto for Antiphonal Organ, graduate recital, 2-10-56, USC
    - LP record album: Etude in E Major Ode for Orchestra, 11-14-43
    - LP record album: Small demo
    - LP record album: Après un Reve, Gabriel Faure (commercial)
  - Subseries C: Recordings, 1963-1993
    - Sub-subseries 1: Orchestra
      - Antiphonal Concerto, USC Retro, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 17)
      - Concerto for Flute (1980-81), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Hester/Harwood, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 34)
      - Concerto for Harpsichord and organ, Roberto Gary, organ, Eiji Hashimoto, Harpsichord, 11/23/1970 (Box 33, Tape 21)
      - Concerto for Organ (1982), Houston, Holloway/Barnard, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 34)
      - Concerto for Organ and Orchestra (1982), world premiere, Members of the Houston Symphony Orchestra, Clyde Holloway, organist, William Barnard, conductor, Christ Church Cathedral, Houston, Texas, 6/2/1982 (Box 31, Tape 27)
      - Concerto for Organ and Orchestra (1982), world premiere, Members of the Houston Symphony Orchestra, Clyde Holloway, organist, William Barnard, conductor, Christ Church Cathedral, Houston, TX, 6/2/1982 (Box 31, Tape 29)
      - Concerto for Sax, excerpts (1982?), Philharmonic Winds of Stockholm, Donald Sinta, sax, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 26)
      - Concerto for Saxophone, Florida State University School of Music, Festival of New Music, April, 1993 (Box 27, Tape 9)
      - Concerto for Saxophone and Winds, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 6)
      - Concerto for Violin and Orchestra, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 13)
      - Concerto for Violin and Orchestra (1967), n.d. (Box 32, Tape 7)
      - Concerto for Winds, Percussion Piano, Ithaca High School Concert Band, Ronald P. Socciarelli, conductor, 2/12/1969 (Box 31, Tape 5)
      - Concerto No 1 for violin and orchestra (1967), Gustave Rosseels, violin; Theo Alcantara, conductor, 10/18/1968 (Box 30, Tape 38)
      - Concerto No 1 for Violin and Orchestra (1967), n.d. (Box 31, Tape 1)
      - Concerto No 1 for Violin and Orchestra (1967), n.d. (Box 33, Tape 24)
      - Descants, L.A.Festival Chamber Orchestra, Milton Thomas, viola, Authur Weisberg, conductor, Schoenberg Hall, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 23)
      - Descants, Chamber Orchestra (UCLA Festival), Milton Thomas, viola; Arthur Weisberg, conductor, 4/12/1975 (Box 31, Tape 26)
      - Double Concerto, L'Orchestre Philharmonique de Monte Carlo, Lawrence Foster, Conductor, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 5)
      - Double Concerto (1985-87), American Premiere, Duo Patterson, L'Orchestre Philharmonic de Monte Carlo, Lawrence Foster, conductor, 4/22/1988 (Box 27, Tape 23)
      - Double Concerto (Composer's note: head missing) (1985-87), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 15)
      - Jubilate (1985-86), n.d. (Box 28, Tape 2)
      - Liturgies (premiere), University of Cincinnati Wind Ensemble, Robert H. Wojciak, conductor, University of Cincinnati, College-Conservatory of Music, Corbett Auditorium, N.B. Includes concert program, 4/25/1971 (Box 29, Tape 7)
      - Liturgies for Winds (1969), CSU Wind Ensemble, Jacob Larson, Conductor, Colorado State University, Dept of Music, Music Building, Concert Hall, A recital of Compositions by Paul Cooper, 4/7/1975 (Box 31, Tape 11)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), 9/30/1990 (Box 25, Tape 26)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), Cleveland chamber symphony, Edwin London, conductor, Concert, 10/1/1990 (Box 27, Tape 40)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), Cleveland chamber symphony, Edwin London, conductor, Recording session, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 41)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), Cleveland chamber symphony, Edwin London, conductor, Recording session, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 42)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), n.d. (Box 28, Tape 1)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), Cleveland chamber symphony, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 3)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), Cleveland chamber symphony, n.d. (Box 28, Tape 7)
      - Love Songs and Dances (1987), n.d. (Box 28, Tape 16)
      - Organ Concerto, Houston Symphony Orchestra, Clyde Holloway, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 36)
      - Organ Concerto, Houston Symphony Orchestra, Clyde Holloway, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 37)
      - Organ Concerto, Houston Symphony Orchestra, Clyde Holloway, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 38)
      - Organ Concerto, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 30)
      - Organ Concerto (1982), Christ Church Cathedral, 3/9/1981 (Box 33, Tape 31)
      - Organ Concerto, first rehearsal, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 14)
      - Organ Concerto, ReelMaster, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 15)
      - Organ Concerto, Rehearsal #2, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 16)
      - Sax Tape No 2, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 1)
      - Saxaphone Concerto, W.A. Academy of Performing Arts, Pat Meighan, sax, Rich Prakhoff, conductor, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 7)
      - Saxophone Concerto, Stockholm Winds, Sinta, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 14)
      - Saxophone concerto, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 13)
      - Saxophone concerto, dress rehearsal, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 12)
      - Sinfonia III: Liturgies for Winds, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 27)
      - Symphony in Two Movements, [Note from composer: bad hum, use other one], 9/12/1983 (Box 29, Tape 22)
      - Symphony in Two Movements, No 5 (1982-83), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 14)
      - Symphony in Two Movements, No 5 (1982-83), Shepherd School Symphony Orchestra, Farbesman, conductor, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 15)
      - Symphony in Two Movements, No 5 (1982-83), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 16)
      - Symphony in Two Movements, No 5 (1982-83), The Slovak Radio and Television Orchestra of Bratislava, Robert Black, conductor, July, 1992, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 17)
      - Symphony in Two Movements, No 5 (1982-83), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 27)
      - Symphony in Two Movements, No 5 (1982-83), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 31)
      - Symphony No 1 'Concertante' (1966), Katims, conductor?, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 11)
      - Symphony No 1, 'Concertante' (1966), Seattle Symphony, Katims, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 20)
      - Symphony No 2, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 2)
      - Symphony No 2 (Antiphons), 5/18/1979 (Box 32, Tape 38)
      - Symphony No 2 'Antiphons' (1971), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 27)
      - Symphony No 2, "Antiphons", University of Ohio Wind Ensemble, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 19)
      - Symphony No 2, "Antiphons" (1971), University of Ohio Wind Ensemble, Lee, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 20)
      - Symphony No 2, 'Antiphons', University of Ohio Wind Ensemble, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 18)
      - Symphony No 3 'Lamentations', n.d. (Box 30, Tape 15)
      - Symphony No 3 'Lamentations' (1971), Congress of Strings Orchestra, Henry Mazer, conductor, Cincinnati, 7/29/1971 (Box 33, Tape 20)
      - Symphony No 3, 'Lamentations' (1971), Congress of Strings, Mazer, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 20)
      - Symphony No 4 (Landscape), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Samuel Jones, conducting, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 19)
      - Symphony No 4 (Landscape), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Samuel Jones, conductor, 9/19/1975 (Box 29, Tape 30)
      - Symphony No 4, Landscape, Houston Symphony Orchestra, Samuel Jones, conductor, James Austin, trumpet, Wayne Crouse, viola, Byron Hester, flute, Commercial tape, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 15)
      - Symphony No 4, Landscape, Houston Symphony Orchestra, Samuel Jones, conductor, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 16)
      - Symphony No 4, 'Landscape' (1973-75), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Jones, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 20)
      - Symphony No 6, Portland Symphony Orchestra, Tashi Shimada, conductor, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 5)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), The Lawrence Symphony Orchestra, 3/5/1989 (Box 24, Tape 6)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christophe Eschenbach, conductor, 3/27/1994 (Box 24, Tape 7)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christophe Eschenbach, conductor, 3/27/1994 (Box 24, Tape 8)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christophe Eschenbach, conductor, 3/27/1994 (Box 24, Tape 9)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christophe Eschenbach, conductor, 3/26/1994 (Box 24, Tape 10)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christophe Eschenbach, conductor, 3/27/1994 (Box 24, Tape 11)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christophe Eschenbach, conductor, 3/27/1994 (Box 24, Tape 12)
      - Symphony No 6 'In Memoriam' (1987), Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christophe Eschenbach, conductor, 3/28/1994 (Box 24, Tape 13)
      - Symphony No. 2 'Antiphons', Ohio University Wind Ensemble, Adrian Gnam, oboe; Thomas Lee, conductor, Kennedy Center, Washington D.C., 5/1/1973 (Box 30, Tape 33)
      - Symphony No3 "Lamentations", College Symphony Orchestra, John Farrer, conductor, Little theater, California State College, Fullerton, 12/10/1971 (Box 30, Tape 4)
      - Variants, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 22)
      - Variants for Orchestra, York Community High School Orchestra, James Plondke, conductor, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 4)